Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ajjames (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Global Management Marketing Strategy Business Strategy

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Programmatic Advertising Foundations

Communicating with Confidence

Delivering an Authentic Elevator Pitch

Leadership: Practical Skills

Developing Your Leadership Philosophy

Honors-Awards

Innovation Judge: Spikes Asia Festival of Creativity

2016 LinkedIn Agency Publisher of the Year - Asia Pacific

LinkedIn Global Goodwill Ambassador

Top 1% - Industry Social Selling Index

2018 LinkedIn Power Profile - Marketing & Advertising

Publications

Anthony James on Tackling Digital Transformation

Young Consumers: Insights and Ideas for Responsible Marketers

Innovation Invigorates Agency Growth

The Maker Movement delivering cutting-edge marketing tech

Anthony J James

Group CEO Innovation & Growth at Trinity Consulting, please click the FOLLOW button for the latest global innovations

Greater Sydney Area

Summary

I believe that, when people are learning, they are growing. I'm on a quest to make excellence a part of those lives that I come in contact with. For me, every day is an opportunity to make the world that I live and work in a better, more creative and more compassionate place.

I'm a lifelong optimist who believes that no mountain is too high to climb, every obstacle has a solution attached to it and even the most far-reaching dreams can be realised with imagination, creativity and resilience. My passion is to help the people I come in contact with turn a great idea into a breakthrough experience that can be seen, touched and felt globally.

I see that obstacles are just opportunities in disguise. Always looking over the next horizon, I am constantly seeking a chance to be a part of that one innovation that can change the way people experience the world.

For nearly 30 years, on four continents, I have helped organisations of all types and sizes learn the art of leadership, influence and technology disruption. My clients learn how to utilise entrepreneurial vision, creative thinking and innovation strategies to become experts in digital, sales, marketing, and brand loyalty. From new startups to big brands, I have helped teams get smarter while the business grows.

Before joining the global consulting ranks with IBM, CSC, Creata and Fujitsu, I was a graphic artist, animator and creative directorall skills that have served me well as I developed my consulting skills. At Trinity Consulting Services, I have been an expert in the commercialisation of new ideas and the global growth of existing businesses in APAC, Europe/EMEA and Australia.

What Makes A Loyal Customer?

Patents
Wine Cube

I am one of LinkedIn's most awarded influencers, recognised as having the 2018 LinkedIn Power Profile - #1 in Marketing & Advertising and 2018 LinkedIn Top Voice (Australia) and Most Influential Agency Voice in Asia Pacific in 2016.

If you want to talk about business growth, strategic direction, creative thinking and operational leadership, I'd love to talk!

Experience

Trinity Consulting Services 4 years 6 months

Group CEO Innovation & Growth April 2020 - Present (5 months) Sydney, New South Wales, Australia

Working closely with clients to help them drive their growth strategy, digital transformation and generate new innovative ideas for global markets.

Executive Director - Marketing, Innovation and Growth March 2016 - Present (4 years 6 months)

APAC - Marketing, Transformation, Digital & Consumer Engagement

Trinity Consulting Services [TCS] is a highly networked marketing strategy, innovation and business transformation agency, that works with brands who have a desire to increase their revenues and market share in some of the largest B2B and B2C markets in APAC (Asia Pacific) and EMEA (Europe, Middle East and Africa).

I specifically help organisations generate additional revenues in these markets with creative, innovative and digital solutions - from up-front strategy to full tactical and practical implementation and roll-out planning.

Leveraging my substantial APAC network and with a deep understanding of cultural differences and in-market influences across the target regions and countries, Trinity Consulting gives its partners the jump-start in digital and innovation that they often lack in penetrating new markets and delivering real, profitable solutions.

TCS blends the creative and the strategic, within a highly flexible and dynamic framework. Assisting organisations to solve complex business problems and issues with the application of technology. Assisting in the packaging,

presenting and pitching of solutions to potential markets, emerging markets and numerous industry verticals.

We have assisted organisations and provided measurable and profitable solutions to: Advertising, Business Travel & Leisure, Consumer Brands, Consumer Marketing, Digital / Online / Social Media, Entertainment, Fast Moving Consumer Goods (FMCG), Financial Services & FINTECH, Franchising, Health & Wellbeing, Information Technology, Media & Publishing, Promotions, Merchandising, Retail, Sports & Sponsorship, Quick Service Restaurants (QSR)

Recent clients include: The Australia Government, Digital Transformation Agency, UNGA, Nokia, News Corp Australia

DDB Group Asia Pacific Chief Innovation & Growth Officer March 2015 - May 2016 (1 year 3 months) Asia Pacific

As Chief Innovation Officer, Asia Pacific, I was tasked with taking head on, the challenge to:

- provide focus to DDB Group's innovative business and marketing growth solutions
- commercialise new and existing digital and tech solutions to generate growth for agency clients
- engage creativity and innovation for drive long-term business growth for agency and clients
- apply creative thinking across business processes to deliver a competitive advantage and new revenue streams
- to connect the best minds within the agency in order to look at business problems from a different perspective

AJ spearheaded the commercial success of innovative digital solutions for DDB's clients – from mobile apps to web-ordering systems to e-stores and interactive retail assets – as well as enhancing client revenue streams and customer engagement to 'hack' into creative business growth opportunities.

Sample Central
Group CEO Marketing and Innovation
December 2007 - March 2015 (7 years 4 months)

Worldwide, Japan, Brazil, USA, Middle East, Eastern Europe (Budapest), UK

Sample Central is a unique retail / consumer product / insights / experience that places a focus on consumers, allowing them to try, touch, feel and experience products, and brand innovations before buying the products. As the pioneer of 'tryvertising' or try-before-you-buy, Sample Central ignites the conversation and interaction between brands and consumers, consumer who are willing to provide their insights about products or services they have chosen to explore or shown and interest in.

Having created the global go-to-market strategy, AJ was the driving-force behind launching the concept to the market, taking an active, hands-on approach selling the concept into brands and growing the business worldwide via a franchise framework.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Took the business global via a franchise model (custom built for the concept)
- Negotiated franchise agreements in over 20 countries in less than 5 years
- Established global and franchise level operational plans and budgets
- Coach, motivate and support new franchisees and business owners
- Play and active and key role selling the concept to brands globally
- Establish clear success metrics, systems and reporting arrangements
- Changed the FMCG landscape with a model that truly influences consumers purchasing decisions
- Built a robust, centralized, big-data engine, SaaS information management and software platform operating in over 10 languages supporting franchise partners and consumers worldwide

Creata

Executive Vice-President Global Sales & Marketing 2004 - December 2007 (3 years)

Worldwide - Asia Pacific, North America, Latin america, Europe, Middle East

Creata is one of the largest marketing and sales promotions agencies in the world, serving some of the largest corporations including McDonald's, Kellogg's, Coca Cola, Nestle, & others since 1973.

AJ took a key leadership role during his time at Creata & was part for the global management team. Working across 15 offices in 11 countries on 5 continents. And was responsible for the design & production of over 1.3 billion happy meal toys.

MAIN RESPONSIBILITIES:

- Setting creative direction and strategy for the agency globally
- Focus the agency on innovation and idea generation built upon creative marketing & promotion strategies
- Transitioned from a premiums manufacturer to a full-service creative & digital agency
- Accelerate the pace of Creata's ability to deliver a full spectrum of below-theline marketing services
- Leadership role in all major account pitches globally & was the driving force of the Company's sales / marketing efforts

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Built and launched Creata Digital
- Positioned Creata to be invited to pitch for global technology pitches with several of the Company's global brand clients
- Secured Creata's first large scale digital project with McDonald's against the incumbent digital agencies
- Extend the HappyMeal.com franchise into Asia Pacific Digital contract extended despite intense lobbying by rival agencies
- Personally managed the relationship and negotiated the deals across North America, Europe & Asia
- Restructured Creata's Creative division from a "Support Function" to a "Business Unit", having full P&L accountability
- Established the relationship & negotiated the contract between Creata & China Central Television (CCTV) to secure the exclusive licensing rights to China's oldest & most recognised cartoon property. Drove the establishment of a separate business entity in the Chinese Free Trade Zone

Fujitsu Consulting - Management Consulting / Digital Solutions Vice-President Marketing & Digital, Asia Pacific 2000 - 2004 (4 years)

Asia Pacific, Australia, New Zealand, Hong Kong, Japan

Fujitsu Consulting is one of the worlds top-tier global IT services organizations. With a focus on boosting efficiencies, cutting IT operational costs and create a sustainable competitive advantage with the client-focused IT consulting and integration services.

As Vice President of Marketing I was responsible for ensuring that clients business objectives were integrally linked to delivering true business value and the offerings of Fujitsu Consulting.

- Directed the strategy, planning and implementation of all Fujitsu Consulting Asia Pacific internal and external corporate marketing activities supporting the business goals toward growth and profitability
- · Focus on solutions marketing
- Ensured a consistent brand and message to the marketplace, making sure corporate style and standards were followed across all initiatives
- Key executive on the Global Brand Program Team
- As Director of eBusiness Solutions, Asia Pacific, provided focus, direction and leadership to position Fujitsu as the partner of choice for eBusiness solutions
- Developed eBusiness solution offerings and the alignment to delivery capabilities

ZIVO Pty Limited - Digital / Web Solutions Director, Sales, Marketing & Communications, Asia Pacific 1999 - 2000 (1 year)

Asia Pacific

- All sales and marketing of Internet Solutions
- Cross-industry focus, managing a team of Business Development Managers across Australia and New Zealand
- Developed a ZIVO-wide business development and acquisition strategy
- Negotiation of all intellectual property and professional services contracts
- Lead engagement management for ZIVO clients including personal management of key accounts
- Major influencer of the ZIVO marketing and branding strategies

IBM Global Services
Managing Consultant - eBusiness, Global
1997 - 1999 (2 years)

- One of the key executives responsible for building and launching the IBM ebusiness Solutions team globally
- Focused on a wide range of industry sectors, specialising in the banking & finance, entertainment, media, sports, travel, transport and tourism sectors across Asia Pacific
- Lead the Asia Pacific sales team to ensure new business sign-off with clients
- Played a leadership role in the relationship build, management and engagement of IBM e-business clients

• Defined strategies for the marketing and sales of e-business and Interactive Media Design Studio services, including: internet/Intranet Solutions, CD-ROM, Kiosk, Electronic-commerce solutions, content creation cybercasting, digital design and print

Computer Sciences Corporation (CSC) Internet Sales & Marketing Manager 1992 - 1997 (5 years)

- Established the MultiMedia Laboratory at CSC in Sydney and grew this to a global capability (and team of 350 people)
- Project managed a variety of multimedia and Internet application design and development and implementation projects
- · Built processes for sales and client engagement
- Full responsibility for major projects being delivered on time and within budget
- Ensured all projects met quality assurance standards of CSC
- Held the position of Worldwide Chair of the CSC Special Interest Group for MultiMedia and Interactive Technologies for 4 years, and through this time spent the majority of time in the United States speaking on the International Speakers Circuit

IBM

Interactive Designer and Programmer February 1987 - February 1992 (5 years 1 month)

Optical & Graphic Services
Graphic Designer / Computer Animator
January 1985 - January 1987 (2 years 1 month)

Optical & Graphic was established in January 1973 creating titles and shooting opticals for films including Peter Weir's Picnic at Hanging Rock, through to titles for Mad Max, The Man from Snowy River and Crocodile Dundee. O & G pioneered the use in Australia of shooting titles onto intermediate stock.

Education

University of Technology, Sydney

Bachelor of Business, Marketing, Communications & Public

Relations, Marketing, Communications & Public Relations · (1990 - 1992)

University of Technology Sydney

Bachelor of Applied Science, Computer Science & Information Science · (1986 - 1990)

Newington College

Higher School Certificate, Business/Commerce, General · (1978 - 1986)

Deep Asia Pacific Market Experience

Marketing, Sales, Growth, Innovation, Commercialisation · (2000 - 2020)